Wensi Wu (she/her/hers)

wuw4@chop.edu | U.S. citizen

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

My research interest lies in utilizing computational analyses to understand the interplay of fluid dynamics and biomechanics in heart muscles, heart valves, and vasculature, to discern a novel understanding of the mechanisms associated with cardiovascular disease. My future research program will situate at the nexus of anatomical shape modeling, physics-based mathematical analysis, and personalized medicine. The theme of my research centers around multi-physics modeling, atrioventricular valve modeling, optimization and uncertainty quantification, and physics-informed machine learning.

EDUCATION

Cornell University Ph.D., Structural Engineering

Ithaca, New York

May 2021

- Dissertation: "Theoretical Formulation for Oblique Free Surface Impact Emanating from Fluid-Structure Interaction Simulations"
- Committee: Christopher Earls (chair), Peter Diamessis, Derek Warner

M.S., Structural Engineering

2018

B.S., Civil Engineering | *Magna Cum Laude*

2015

ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

Children's Hospital of Philadelphia | NIH T32 Trainee in Cardiology

2022-Now

Mentors: Drs. Matthew A. Jolley, Alison M. Pouch, Lu Lu, and Kevin T. Turner

• Develop a physics-informed machine learning framework for learning atrioventricular heart valve mechanical properties from medical images.

Children's Hospital of Philadelphia | Postdoctoral Fellow

2021-Now

Mentors: Drs. Matthew A. Jolley, Jeffrey A. Weiss, and Andras Lasso

• Studied the effects of leaflet mechanical properties on the resulting function of pathological mitral valves.

Cornell University | *Graduate Research Assistant*

2015-2021

Mentor: Dr. Christopher Earls

 Developed a simple and accurate engineering theory for hydrodynamic slamming using high fidelity fluid-structure interaction analyses.

Sandia National Laboratories | Visiting Researcher

Summer 2017

Mentors: Drs. Robert Kuether, Matthew Allen, and Paolo Tiso

• Implemented regularized Coulomb friction subroutine to study the influence of friction in the contact interface of jointed structure.

Duke University | *NSF REU Fellow*

Summer 2014

Mentor: Dr. Guglielmo Scovazzi

• Studied the resulting pressure distribution of a brain model subjected to blast loading through fluid-structure interaction simulations.

University of Cincinnati | *NSF REU Fellow*

Summer 2013

Mentors: Drs. Margaret Kupferle and George Sorial

• Conducted experimental studies to evaluate the contaminant absorption performance between commercial activated carbon and in-house developed activated carbon.

Updated: July 3, 2023 W. Wu | 1/4

REFEREED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **W. Wu**, M. Daneker, M.A. Jolley, K.T. Turner, L. Lu* (2023) "Effective data sampling strategies and boundary condition constraints of physics-informed neural networks for identifying material properties in solid mechanics," Applied Mathematics and Mechanics, Vol. 44, Springer, 1039.
- 2. **W. Wu**, S. Ching, P. Sabin, D.W. Laurence, S.A. Maas, A. Lasso, J.A. Weiss, M.A. Jolley* (2023) "The effects of leaflet material properties on the simulated function of regurgitant mitral valves," Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials, Vol. 142, Elsevier, 105858.
- 3. W. Wu, S. Ching, S.A. Maas, A. Lasso, P. Sabin, J.A. Weiss, M.A. Jolley* (2022) "A computational framework for atrioventricular valve modeling using open-source software," Journal of Biomechanical Engineering, Vol. 144, ASME, 101012.
- 4. **W. Wu***, C.J. Earls (2022) "A new engineering theory describing oblique free surface impact by flexible plates," Ocean Engineering, Vol 256, Elsevier, 111473.
- 5. **W. Wu***, C. Bonneville, C.J. Earls (2021) "A principled approach to design using high fidelity fluid-structure interaction simulations," Finite Element in Analysis & Design, Vol. 194, Elsevier, 103562.
- 6. **W. Wu***, J.W. Kosianka, H.M. Reed, C.J. Stull, and C.J. Earls (2020) "CU-BENs: A structural finite element library," SoftwareX, Vol. 11, Elsevier, 1.
- * Denotes corresponding author

REFEREED CONFERENCE PROCEEDING

1. P.J. Hughes, W. Scott, W. Wu, R.J. Kuether, M.S. Allen, and P. Tiso (2019) "Interface Reduction on Hurty/Craig-Bampton Substructures with Frictionless Contact", In: Kerschen G. (eds) Nonlinear Dynamics, Volume 1. Conference Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Mechanics Series. Springer, Cham.

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

- 1. **W. Wu***, M. Daneker, M.A. Jolley, K.T. Turner, L. Lu (2023) "Effective Physics-Informed Machine Learning Strategies for Material Identification," 17th U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics, Albuquerque, New Mexico.
- 2. **W. Wu*** and L. Lu (2023) "Machine Learning for Material Designs," *MACH 2023*, Baltimore, Maryland.
- 3. **W. Wu*** and C.J. Earls (2021) "Towards a Generalized Engineering Theory for Hydrodynamic Slamming Emanating from Partitioned Fluid-Structure Interaction Analysis," 16th U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics, Virtual.
- 4. **W. Wu*** and C.J. Earls (2019) "Tightly Coupled, Partitioned Fluid-Structure Interaction Analysis of a Horizontal Plate Impact onto a Water Free Surface: Computational Framework and Validation," 15th U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics, Austin, Texas.
- 5. **W. Wu*** and C.J. Earls (2018) "Open Source, Tightly Coupled, Partitioned Fluid-Structure Interaction Modeling Framework for Naval Applications: The Impact of Slamming Loads on High Speed Watercraft," 13th World Congress on Computational Mechanics, New York City, New York.
- 6. P.J. Hughes*, W. Scott, **W. Wu**, R.J. Kuether, M.S. Allen, and P. Tiso (2018) "Interface Reduction on Hurty/Craig-Bampton Substructures with Frictionless Contact," *IMAC Annual Meeting*, Orlando, Florida.

Updated: July 3, 2023 W. Wu | 2/4

- 7. **W. Wu***, J.W. Kosianka, and C.J. Earls (2017) "Open Source, Tightly Coupled, Partitioned Fluid-Structure Interaction Simulation Capability for High Spatiotemporal Resolution During Study of Wave Impact Loads in High Speed Watercraft," 14th U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics, Montreal, Canada.
- 8. J.W. Kosianka*, **W. Wu**, and C.J. Earls (2017) "Condition Assessment and Prognosis using Fluid-Structure Interaction within a Reduced-Order Model Tracking Inversion Framework," 14th U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics, Montreal, Canada.

SEMINAR TALKS

- 1. **W. Wu** (2023) "Discovering the Material Properties of Soft Tissue Through Machine Learning," Children's Hospital of Philadelphia Cardiology Research Training Seminar.
- 2. W. Wu (2022) "Toward Patient-Specific Computational Modeling of Tricuspid Valve Repair in Hypoplastic Left Heart Syndrome," Children's Hospital of Philadelphia Cardiology Research Training Seminar.

HONORS AND AWARDS

Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Award (NRSA) Institutional Research	2022-2024
Training Fellowship, National Heart Lung and Blood Institute (T32)	
U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics Conference Travel Award	2023
Cornell University Conference Travel Grant	2017–2019
Cornell University Ve-Sing and Tseng So Koo Award	2015
National Science Foundation Sponsored Research Experiences for Undergraduates Best C	Over- 2013
all Project	

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Cornell University Teaching Assistant	Spring 2019
CEE 4740: Introduction to The Behavior of Metal Structures	
Cornell University Guest Lecturer	Summer 2018
CEE 3720: Intermediate Solid Mechanics	
Cornell University Teaching Assistant	Spring 2018
CEE 4780/6780: Structural Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering	1 0

GRANT WRITING EXPERIENCE

Title: A Novel, Non-invasive Computational Approach for Determining the Etiology of Tricuspid Regurgitation in Patients With Hypoplastic Left Heart Syndrome

Funding Mechanism: NRSA T32 Training Grant at the Children's Hospital of Philadel-

phia, Division of Pediatric Cardiology

Period of Support: July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2024

Level of Support: \$117,185

Program Director: Robert J. Levy
Principal Investigator

Proposal Contributions: Writing, reviewing, and editing the research proposal

Title: Deep Learning and Physics Informed Neural Networks to Advance Single Ventricle Atrioventricular Valve Modeling

Updated: July 3, 2023 W. Wu | 3/4

^{*} Denotes presenter

Funding Mechanism: Additional Ventures Expansion Award

Period of Support: July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023

Level of Support: \$50,000

Principal Investigator: Matthew Jolley **Role:** Co-Investigator

Proposal Contributions: Writing, reviewing, and editing the research proposal

Title: Partitioned Approach, Implicit Fluid-Structure Interaction for the Study of Hydroelastic Effects in High

Speed Watercraft

Funding Mechanism: National Science Foundation, XSEDE **Period of Support:** April 20, 2020 to April 19, 2021

Level of Support: CPUs worth \$1,157
Principal Investigator: Christopher Earls
Role: Primary Investigator

Proposal Contributions: Writing, reviewing, and editing the research proposal

MENTORING EXPERIENCE

Children's Hospital of Philadelphia	
Mitchell Daneker PhD student at University of Pennsylvania	2021-Present
Silvani Amin Incoming PhD student at University of Pennsylvania	2021-Present
Stephen Ching Research Assistant at the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia	2021-Present
Cornell University	
Christophe Bonneville Postdoctoral Researcher at Sandia National Laboratories	2018-2021
Dana Luong Incoming PhD student at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine	2018-Present
Angela Jin PhD student at the University of California, Berkeley	2018-2020

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania	
Biomedical Postdoctoral Council Career and Training Committee	2022-2023
Cornell University	
CEE Graduate Student Association Vice President	2020-2021
Sport Taekwondo Student Club Treasurer and Practice Leader	2019-2021
Engineering TA Development Program TA Development Consultant	2018-2019
CEE Graduate Student Association Treasurer	2016-2017
Chi Epsilon National Civil Engineering Honor Society Treasurer	2014–2015
American Society of Civil Engineers	2013-2014
2014 ASCE Upstate NY Region Student Conference Committee	
International High School at Prospect Heights	
International Dreamers Scholarship Fund Selection Committee	2018-Present

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

2023 Intersections Science Fellows Symposium Application Reviewer	2023
2023 Science Slam Competition at the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia Abstract Reviewer	2023
Biomedical Postdoctoral Research Symposium at University of Pennsylvania Abstract Re-	2022
viewer	

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

U. S. Association for Computational Mechanics Tau Beta Pi National Engineering Honor Society Chi Epsilon National Civil Engineering Honor Society American Society of Civil Engineers

Updated: July 3, 2023 W. Wu | 4/4